{
  "Technician": [
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is part of the Basis and Purpose of the Amateur Radio Service?",
      "answer": "Advancing skills in the technical and communication phases of the radio art"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which agency regulates and enforces the rules for the Amateur Radio Service in the United States?",
      "answer": "The FCC"
    },
    {
      "question": "What do the FCC rules state regarding the use of a phonetic alphabet for station identification in the Amateur Radio Service?",
      "answer": "It is encouraged"
    },
    {
      "question": "How many operator/primary station license grants may be held by any one person?",
      "answer": "One"
    },
    {
      "question": "What proves that the FCC has issued an operator/primary license grant?",
      "answer": "The license appears in the FCC ULS database"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the FCC Part 97 definition of a beacon?",
      "answer": "An amateur station transmitting communications for the purposes of observing propagation or related experimental activities"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the FCC Part 97 definition of a space station?",
      "answer": "An amateur station located more than 50 km above Earth's surface"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following entities recommends transmit/receive channels and other parameters for auxiliary and repeater stations?",
      "answer": "Volunteer Frequency Coordinator recognized by local amateurs"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who selects a Frequency Coordinator?",
      "answer": "Amateur operators in a local or regional area whose stations are eligible to be repeater or auxiliary stations"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the Radio Amateur Civil Emergency Service (RACES)?",
      "answer": "All these choices are correct"
    },
    {
      "question": "When is willful interference to other amateur radio stations permitted?",
      "answer": "At no time"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following frequency ranges are available for phone operation by Technician licensees?",
      "answer": "28.300 MHz to 28.500 MHz"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which amateurs may contact the International Space Station (ISS) on VHF bands?",
      "answer": "Any amateur holding a Technician class or higher license"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which frequency is in the 6 meter amateur band?",
      "answer": "52.525 MHz"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which amateur band includes 146.52 MHz?",
      "answer": "2 meters"
    },
    {
      "question": "How may amateurs use the 219 to 220 MHz segment of 1.25 meter band?",
      "answer": "Fixed digital message forwarding systems only"
    },
    {
      "question": "On which HF bands does a Technician class operator have phone privileges?",
      "answer": "10 meter band only"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following VHF/UHF band segments are limited to CW only?",
      "answer": "50.0 MHz to 50.1 MHz and 144.0 MHz to 144.1 MHz"
    },
    {
      "question": "How are US amateurs restricted in segments of bands where the Amateur Radio Service is secondary?",
      "answer": "U.S. amateurs may find non-amateur stations in those segments, and must avoid interfering with them"
    },
    {
      "question": "Why should you not set your transmit frequency to be exactly at the edge of an amateur band or sub-band?",
      "answer": "All these choices are correct"
    },
    {
      "question": "Where may SSB phone be used in amateur bands above 50 MHz?",
      "answer": "In at least some segment of all these bands"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the maximum peak envelope power output for Technician class operators in their HF band segments?",
      "answer": "200 watts"
    },
    {
      "question": "Except for some specific restrictions, what is the maximum peak envelope power output for Technician class operators using frequencies above 30 MHz?",
      "answer": "1500 watts"
    },
    {
      "question": "For which license classes are new licenses currently available from the FCC?",
      "answer": "Technician, General, Amateur Extra"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who may select a desired call sign under the vanity call sign rules?",
      "answer": "Any licensed amateur"
    },
    {
      "question": "What types of international communications are an FCC-licensed amateur radio station permitted to make?",
      "answer": "Communications incidental to the purposes of the Amateur Radio Service and remarks of a personal character"
    },
    {
      "question": "What may happen if the FCC is unable to reach you by email?",
      "answer": "Revocation of the station license or suspension of the operator license"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a valid Technician class call sign format?",
      "answer": "KF1XXX"
    },
    {
      "question": "From which of the following locations may an FCC-licensed amateur station transmit?",
      "answer": "From any vessel or craft located in international waters and documented or registered in the United States"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following can result in revocation of the station license or suspension of the operator license?",
      "answer": "Failure to provide and maintain a correct email address with the FCC"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the normal term for an FCC-issued amateur radio license?",
      "answer": "Ten years"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the grace period for renewal if an amateur license expires?",
      "answer": "Two years"
    },
    {
      "question": "How soon after passing the examination for your first amateur radio license may you transmit on the amateur radio bands?",
      "answer": "As soon as your operator/station license grant appears in the FCC’s license database"
    },
    {
      "question": "If your license has expired and is still within the allowable grace period, may you continue to transmit on the amateur radio bands?",
      "answer": "No, you must wait until the license has been renewed"
    },
    {
      "question": "With which countries are FCC-licensed amateur radio stations prohibited from exchanging communications?",
      "answer": "Any country whose administration has notified the International Telecommunication Union (ITU) that it objects to such communications"
    },
    {
      "question": "Under which of the following circumstances are one-way transmissions by an amateur station prohibited?",
      "answer": "Broadcasting"
    },
    {
      "question": "When is it permissible to transmit messages encoded to obscure their meaning?",
      "answer": "Only when transmitting control commands to space stations or radio control craft"
    },
    {
      "question": "Under what conditions is an amateur station authorized to transmit music using a phone emission?",
      "answer": "When incidental to an authorized retransmission of manned spacecraft communications"
    },
    {
      "question": "When may amateur radio operators use their stations to notify other amateurs of the availability of equipment for sale or trade?",
      "answer": "When selling amateur radio equipment and not on a regular basis"
    },
    {
      "question": "What, if any, are the restrictions concerning transmission of language that may be considered indecent or obscene?",
      "answer": "Any such language is prohibited"
    },
    {
      "question": "What types of amateur stations can automatically retransmit the signals of other amateur stations?",
      "answer": "Repeater, auxiliary, or space stations"
    },
    {
      "question": "In which of the following circumstances may the control operator of an amateur station receive compensation for operating that station?",
      "answer": "When the communication is incidental to classroom instruction at an educational institution"
    },
    {
      "question": "When may amateur stations transmit information in support of broadcasting, program production, or news gathering, assuming no other means is available?",
      "answer": "When such communications are directly related to the immediate safety of human life or protection of property"
    },
    {
      "question": "How does the FCC define broadcasting for the Amateur Radio Service?",
      "answer": "Transmissions intended for reception by the general public"
    },
    {
      "question": "When may an amateur station transmit without identifying on the air?",
      "answer": "When transmitting signals to control model craft"
    },
    {
      "question": "When may an amateur station transmit without a control operator?",
      "answer": "Never"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who may be the control operator of a station communicating through an amateur satellite or space station?",
      "answer": "Any amateur allowed to transmit on the satellite uplink frequency"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who must designate the station control operator?",
      "answer": "The station licensee"
    },
    {
      "question": "What determines the transmitting frequency privileges of an amateur station?",
      "answer": "The class of operator license held by the control operator"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is an amateur station control point?",
      "answer": "The location at which the control operator function is performed"
    },
    {
      "question": "When, under normal circumstances, may a Technician class licensee be the control operator of a station operating in an Amateur Extra Class band segment?",
      "answer": "At no time"
    },
    {
      "question": "When the control operator is not the station licensee, who is responsible for the proper operation of the station?",
      "answer": "The control operator and the station licensee"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is an example of automatic control?",
      "answer": "Repeater operation"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following are required for remote control operation?",
      "answer": "All these choices are correct"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is an example of remote control as defined in Part 97?",
      "answer": "Operating the station over the internet"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who does the FCC presume to be the control operator of an amateur station, unless documentation to the contrary is in the station records?",
      "answer": "The station licensee"
    },
    {
      "question": "When must the station and its records be available for FCC inspection?",
      "answer": "At any time upon request by an FCC representative"
    },
    {
      "question": "How often must you identify with your FCC-assigned call sign when using tactical call signs such as “Race Headquarters”?",
      "answer": "At the end of each communication and every ten minutes during a communication"
    },
    {
      "question": "When are you required to transmit your assigned call sign?",
      "answer": "At least every 10 minutes during and at the end of a communication"
    },
    {
      "question": "What language may you use for identification when operating in a phone sub-band?",
      "answer": "English"
    },
    {
      "question": "What method of call sign identification is required for a station transmitting phone signals?",
      "answer": "Send the call sign using a CW or phone emission"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following self-assigned indicators are acceptable when using a phone transmission?",
      "answer": "All these choices are correct"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following restrictions apply when a non-licensed person is allowed to speak to a foreign station using a station under the control of a licensed amateur operator?",
      "answer": "The foreign station must be in a country with which the U.S. has a third party agreement"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the definition of third party communications?",
      "answer": "A message from a control operator to another amateur station control operator on behalf of another person"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of amateur station simultaneously retransmits the signal of another amateur station on a different channel or channels?",
      "answer": "Repeater station"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is accountable if a repeater inadvertently retransmits communications that violate the FCC rules?",
      "answer": "The control operator of the originating station"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a requirement for the issuance of a club station license grant?",
      "answer": "The club must have at least four members"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a common repeater frequency offset in the 2 meter band?",
      "answer": "Plus or minus 600 kHz"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the national calling frequency for FM simplex operations in the 2 meter band?",
      "answer": "146.520 MHz"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a common repeater frequency offset in the 70 cm band?",
      "answer": "Plus or minus 5 MHz"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is an appropriate way to call another station on a repeater if you know the other station's call sign?",
      "answer": "Say the station's call sign, then identify with your call sign"
    },
    {
      "question": "How should you respond to a station calling CQ?",
      "answer": "Transmit the other station’s call sign followed by your call sign"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is required when making on-the-air test transmissions?",
      "answer": "Identify the transmitting station"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is meant by \"repeater offset\"?",
      "answer": "The difference between a repeater’s transmit and receive frequencies"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the meaning of the procedural signal “CQ”?",
      "answer": "Calling any station"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following indicates that a station is listening on a repeater and looking for a contact?",
      "answer": "The station’s call sign followed by the word \"monitoring\""
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a band plan, beyond the privileges established by the FCC?",
      "answer": "A voluntary guideline for using different modes or activities within an amateur band"
    },
    {
      "question": "What term describes an amateur station that is transmitting and receiving on the same frequency?",
      "answer": "Simplex"
    },
    {
      "question": "What should you do before calling CQ?",
      "answer": "All these choices are correct"
    },
    {
      "question": "How is a VHF/UHF transceiver’s “reverse” function used?",
      "answer": "To listen on a repeater’s input frequency"
    },
    {
      "question": "What term describes the use of a sub-audible tone transmitted along with normal voice audio to open the squelch of a receiver?",
      "answer": "CTCSS"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following describes a linked repeater network?",
      "answer": "A network of repeaters in which signals received by one repeater are transmitted by all the repeaters in the network"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following could be the reason you are unable to access a repeater whose output you can hear?",
      "answer": "All these choices are correct"
    },
    {
      "question": "What would cause your FM transmission audio to be distorted on voice peaks?",
      "answer": "You are talking too loudly"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of signaling uses pairs of audio tones?",
      "answer": "DTMF"
    },
    {
      "question": "How can you join a digital repeater’s “talkgroup”?",
      "answer": "Program your radio with the group’s ID or code"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following applies when two stations transmitting on the same frequency interfere with each other?",
      "answer": "The stations should negotiate continued use of the frequency"
    },
    {
      "question": "Why are simplex channels designated in the VHF/UHF band plans?",
      "answer": "So stations within range of each other can communicate without tying up a repeater"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which Q signal indicates that you are receiving interference from other stations?",
      "answer": "QRM"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which Q signal indicates that you are changing frequency?",
      "answer": "QSY"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of the color code used on DMR repeater systems?",
      "answer": "Must match the repeater color code for access"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of a squelch function?",
      "answer": "Mute the receiver audio when a signal is not present"
    },
    {
      "question": "When do FCC rules NOT apply to the operation of an amateur station?",
      "answer": "FCC rules always apply"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following are typical duties of a Net Control Station?",
      "answer": "Call the net to order and direct communications between stations checking in"
    },
    {
      "question": "What technique is used to ensure that voice messages containing unusual words are received correctly?",
      "answer": "Spell the words using a standard phonetic alphabet"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is RACES?",
      "answer": "An FCC part 97 amateur radio service for civil defense communications during national emergencies"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the term “traffic” refer to in net operation?",
      "answer": "Messages exchanged by net stations"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the Amateur Radio Emergency Service (ARES)?",
      "answer": "A group of licensed amateurs who have voluntarily registered their qualifications and equipment for communications duty in the public service"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is standard practice when you participate in a net?",
      "answer": "Unless you are reporting an emergency, transmit only when directed by the net control station"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a characteristic of good traffic handling?",
      "answer": "Passing messages exactly as received"
    },
    {
      "question": "Are amateur station control operators ever permitted to operate outside the frequency privileges of their license class?",
      "answer": "Yes, but only in situations involving the immediate safety of human life or protection of property"
    },
    {
      "question": "What information is contained in the preamble of a formal traffic message?",
      "answer": "Information needed to track the message"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is meant by “check” in a radiogram header?",
      "answer": "The number of words or word equivalents in the text portion of the message"
    },
    {
      "question": "Why do VHF signal strengths sometimes vary greatly when the antenna is moved only a few feet?",
      "answer": "Multipath propagation cancels or reinforces signals"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the effect of vegetation on UHF and microwave signals?",
      "answer": "Absorption"
    },
    {
      "question": "What antenna polarization is normally used for long-distance CW and SSB contacts on the VHF and UHF bands?",
      "answer": "Horizontal"
    },
    {
      "question": "What happens when antennas at opposite ends of a VHF or UHF line of sight radio link are not using the same polarization?",
      "answer": "Received signal strength is reduced"
    },
    {
      "question": "When using a directional antenna, how might your station be able to communicate with a distant repeater if buildings or obstructions are blocking the direct line of sight path?",
      "answer": "Try to find a path that reflects signals to the repeater"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the meaning of the term “picket fencing”?",
      "answer": "Rapid flutter on mobile signals due to multipath propagation"
    },
    {
      "question": "What weather condition might decrease range at microwave frequencies?",
      "answer": "Precipitation"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a likely cause of irregular fading of signals propagated by the ionosphere?",
      "answer": "Random combining of signals arriving via different paths"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following results from the fact that signals propagated by the ionosphere are elliptically polarized?",
      "answer": "Either vertically or horizontally polarized antennas may be used for transmission or reception"
    },
    {
      "question": "What effect does multi-path propagation have on data transmissions?",
      "answer": "Error rates are likely to increase"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which region of the atmosphere can refract or bend HF and VHF radio waves?",
      "answer": "The ionosphere"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the effect of fog and rain on signals in the 10 meter and 6 meter bands?",
      "answer": "There is little effect"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the relationship between the electric and magnetic fields of an electromagnetic wave?",
      "answer": "They are at right angles"
    },
    {
      "question": "What property of a radio wave defines its polarization?",
      "answer": "The orientation of the electric field"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the two components of a radio wave?",
      "answer": "Electric and magnetic fields"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the velocity of a radio wave traveling through free space?",
      "answer": "Speed of light"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the relationship between wavelength and frequency?",
      "answer": "Wavelength gets shorter as frequency increases"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the formula for converting frequency to approximate wavelength in meters?",
      "answer": "Wavelength in meters equals 300 divided by frequency in megahertz"
    },
    {
      "question": "In addition to frequency, which of the following is used to identify amateur radio bands?",
      "answer": "The approximate wavelength in meters"
    },
    {
      "question": "What frequency range is referred to as VHF?",
      "answer": "30 MHz to 300 MHz"
    },
    {
      "question": "What frequency range is referred to as UHF?",
      "answer": "300 to 3000 MHz"
    },
    {
      "question": "What frequency range is referred to as HF?",
      "answer": "3 to 30 MHz"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the approximate velocity of a radio wave in free space?",
      "answer": "300,000,000 meters per second"
    },
    {
      "question": "Why are simplex UHF signals rarely heard beyond their radio horizon?",
      "answer": "UHF signals are usually not propagated by the ionosphere"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a characteristic of HF communication compared with communications on VHF and higher frequencies?",
      "answer": "Long-distance ionospheric propagation is far more common on HF"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a characteristic of VHF signals received via auroral backscatter?",
      "answer": "They are distorted and signal strength varies considerably"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following types of propagation is most commonly associated with occasional strong signals on the 10, 6, and 2 meter bands from beyond the radio horizon?",
      "answer": "Sporadic E"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following effects may allow radio signals to travel beyond obstructions between the transmitting and receiving stations?",
      "answer": "Knife-edge diffraction"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of propagation is responsible for allowing over-the-horizon VHF and UHF communications to ranges of approximately 300 miles on a regular basis?",
      "answer": "Tropospheric ducting"
    },
    {
      "question": "What band is best suited for communicating via meteor scatter?",
      "answer": "6 meters"
    },
    {
      "question": "What causes tropospheric ducting?",
      "answer": "Temperature inversions in the atmosphere"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is generally the best time for long-distance 10 meter band propagation via the F region?",
      "answer": "From dawn to shortly after sunset during periods of high sunspot activity"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following bands may provide long-distance communications via the ionosphere’s F region during the peak of the sunspot cycle?",
      "answer": "6 and 10 meters"
    },
    {
      "question": "Why is the radio horizon for VHF and UHF signals more distant than the visual horizon?",
      "answer": "The atmosphere refracts radio waves slightly"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is an appropriate power supply rating for a typical 50 watt output mobile FM transceiver?",
      "answer": "13.8 volts at 12 amperes"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following should be considered when selecting an accessory SWR meter?",
      "answer": "The frequency and power level at which the measurements will be made"
    },
    {
      "question": "Why are short, heavy-gauge wires used for a transceiver’s DC power connection?",
      "answer": "To minimize voltage drop when transmitting"
    },
    {
      "question": "How are the transceiver audio input and output connected in a station configured to operate using FT8?",
      "answer": "To the audio input and output of a computer running WSJT-X software"
    },
    {
      "question": "Where should an RF power meter be installed?",
      "answer": "In the feed line, between the transmitter and antenna"
    },
    {
      "question": "What signals are used in a computer-radio interface for digital mode operation?",
      "answer": "Receive audio, transmit audio, and transmitter keying"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following connections is made between a computer and a transceiver to use computer software when operating digital modes?",
      "answer": "Computer “line in” to transceiver speaker connector"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following conductors is preferred for bonding at RF?",
      "answer": "Flat copper strap"
    },
    {
      "question": "How can you determine the length of time that equipment can be powered from a battery?",
      "answer": "Divide the battery ampere-hour rating by the average current draw of the equipment"
    },
    {
      "question": "What function is performed with a transceiver and a digital mode hot spot?",
      "answer": "Communication using digital voice or data systems via the internet"
    },
    {
      "question": "Where should the negative power return of a mobile transceiver be connected in a vehicle?",
      "answer": "At the 12 volt battery chassis ground"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is an electronic keyer?",
      "answer": "A device that assists in manual sending of Morse code"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the effect of excessive microphone gain on SSB transmissions?",
      "answer": "Distorted transmitted audio"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following can be used to enter a transceiver’s operating frequency?",
      "answer": "The keypad or VFO knob"
    },
    {
      "question": "How is squelch adjusted so that a weak FM signal can be heard?",
      "answer": "Set the squelch threshold so that receiver output audio is on all the time"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a way to enable quick access to a favorite frequency or channel on your transceiver?",
      "answer": "Store it in a memory channel"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the scanning function of an FM transceiver do?",
      "answer": "Tunes through a range of frequencies to check for activity"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following controls could be used if the voice pitch of a single-sideband signal returning to your CQ call seems too high or low?",
      "answer": "The RIT or Clarifier"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does a DMR “code plug” contain?",
      "answer": "Access information for repeaters and talkgroups"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the advantage of having multiple receive bandwidth choices on a multimode transceiver?",
      "answer": "Permits noise or interference reduction by selecting a bandwidth matching the mode"
    },
    {
      "question": "How is a specific group of stations selected on a digital voice transceiver?",
      "answer": "By entering the group's identification code"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following receiver filter bandwidths provides the best signal-to-noise ratio for SSB reception?",
      "answer": "2400 Hz"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following must be programmed into a D-STAR digital transceiver before transmitting?",
      "answer": "Your call sign"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the result of tuning an FM receiver above or below a signal's frequency?",
      "answer": "Distortion of the signal's audio"
    },
    {
      "question": "Electrical current is measured in which of the following units?",
      "answer": "Amperes"
    },
    {
      "question": "Electrical power is measured in which of the following units?",
      "answer": "Watts"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name for the flow of electrons in an electric circuit?",
      "answer": "Current"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the units of electrical resistance?",
      "answer": "Ohms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the electrical term for the force that causes electron flow?",
      "answer": "Voltage"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the unit of frequency?",
      "answer": "Hertz"
    },
    {
      "question": "Why are metals generally good conductors of electricity?",
      "answer": "They have many free electrons"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a good electrical insulator?",
      "answer": "Glass"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following describes alternating current?",
      "answer": "Current that alternates between positive and negative directions"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which term describes the rate at which electrical energy is used?",
      "answer": "Power"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of current flow is opposed by resistance?",
      "answer": "All these choices are correct"
    },
    {
      "question": "What describes the number of times per second that an alternating current makes a complete cycle?",
      "answer": "Frequency"
    },
    {
      "question": "How many milliamperes is 1.5 amperes?",
      "answer": "1500 milliamperes"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is equal to 1,500,000 hertz?",
      "answer": "1500 kHz"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is equal to one kilovolt?",
      "answer": "One thousand volts"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is equal to one microvolt?",
      "answer": "One one-millionth of a volt"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is equal to 500 milliwatts?",
      "answer": "0.5 watts"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is equal to 3,000 milliamperes?",
      "answer": "3 amperes"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is equal to 3.525 MHz?",
      "answer": "3525 kHz"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is equal to 1,000,000 picofarads?",
      "answer": "1 microfarad"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which decibel value most closely represents a power increase from 5 watts to 10 watts?",
      "answer": "3 dB"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which decibel value most closely represents a power decrease from 12 watts to 3 watts?",
      "answer": "-6 dB"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which decibel value represents a power increase from 20 watts to 200 watts?",
      "answer": "10 dB"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is equal to 28400 kHz?",
      "answer": "28.400 MHz"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is equal to 2425 MHz?",
      "answer": "2.425 GHz"
    },
    {
      "question": "What describes the ability to store energy in an electric field?",
      "answer": "Capacitance"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the unit of capacitance?",
      "answer": "The farad"
    },
    {
      "question": "What describes the ability to store energy in a magnetic field?",
      "answer": "Inductance"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the unit of inductance?",
      "answer": "The henry"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the unit of impedance?",
      "answer": "The ohm"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the abbreviation RF mean?",
      "answer": "Radio frequency signals of all types"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the abbreviation for megahertz?",
      "answer": "MHz"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the formula used to calculate electrical power (P) in a DC circuit?",
      "answer": "P = I × E"
    },
    {
      "question": "How much power is delivered by a voltage of 13.8 volts DC and a current of 10 amperes?",
      "answer": "138 watts"
    },
    {
      "question": "How much power is delivered by a voltage of 12 volts DC and a current of 2.5 amperes?",
      "answer": "30 watts"
    },
    {
      "question": "How much current is required to deliver 120 watts at a voltage of 12 volts DC?",
      "answer": "10 amperes"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is impedance?",
      "answer": "The opposition to AC current flow"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the abbreviation for kilohertz?",
      "answer": "kHz"
    },
    {
      "question": "What formula is used to calculate current in a circuit?",
      "answer": "I = E / R"
    },
    {
      "question": "What formula is used to calculate voltage in a circuit?",
      "answer": "E = I × R"
    },
    {
      "question": "What formula is used to calculate resistance in a circuit?",
      "answer": "R = E / I"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the resistance of a circuit in which a current of 3 amperes flows when connected to 90 volts?",
      "answer": "30 ohms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the resistance of a circuit for which the applied voltage is 12 volts and the current flow is 1.5 amperes?",
      "answer": "8 ohms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the resistance of a circuit that draws 4 amperes from a 12-volt source?",
      "answer": "3 ohms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the current in a circuit with an applied voltage of 120 volts and a resistance of 80 ohms?",
      "answer": "1.5 amperes"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the current through a 100-ohm resistor connected across 200 volts?",
      "answer": "2 amperes"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the current through a 24-ohm resistor connected across 240 volts?",
      "answer": "10 amperes"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the voltage across a 2-ohm resistor if a current of 0.5 amperes flows through it?",
      "answer": "1 volt"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the voltage across a 10-ohm resistor if a current of 1 ampere flows through it?",
      "answer": "10 volts"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the voltage across a 10-ohm resistor if a current of 2 amperes flows through it?",
      "answer": "20 volts"
    },
    {
      "question": "In which type of circuit is DC current the same through all components?",
      "answer": "Series"
    },
    {
      "question": "In which type of circuit is voltage the same across all components?",
      "answer": "Parallel"
    },
    {
      "question": "What electrical component opposes the flow of current in a DC circuit?",
      "answer": "Resistor"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of component is often used as an adjustable volume control?",
      "answer": "Potentiometer"
    },
    {
      "question": "What electrical parameter is controlled by a potentiometer?",
      "answer": "Resistance"
    },
    {
      "question": "What electrical component stores energy in an electric field?",
      "answer": "Capacitor"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of electrical component consists of conductive surfaces separated by an insulator?",
      "answer": "Capacitor"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of electrical component stores energy in a magnetic field?",
      "answer": "Inductor"
    },
    {
      "question": "What electrical component is typically constructed as a coil of wire?",
      "answer": "Inductor"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the function of an SPDT switch?",
      "answer": "A single circuit is switched between one of two other circuits"
    },
    {
      "question": "What electrical component is used to protect other circuit components from current overloads?",
      "answer": "Fuse"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following battery chemistries is rechargeable?",
      "answer": "All these choices are correct"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following battery chemistries is not rechargeable?",
      "answer": "Carbon-zinc"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of switch is represented by component 3 in figure T-2?",
      "answer": "Single-pole single-throw"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is true about forward voltage drop in a diode?",
      "answer": "It is lower in some diode types than in others"
    },
    {
      "question": "What electronic component allows current to flow in only one direction?",
      "answer": "Diode"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these components can be used as an electronic switch?",
      "answer": "Transistor"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following components can consist of three regions of semiconductor material?",
      "answer": "Transistor"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of transistor has a gate, drain, and source?",
      "answer": "Field-effect"
    },
    {
      "question": "How is the cathode lead of a semiconductor diode often marked on the package?",
      "answer": "With a stripe"
    },
    {
      "question": "What causes a light-emitting diode (LED) to emit light?",
      "answer": "Forward current"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the abbreviation FET stand for?",
      "answer": "Field Effect Transistor"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the names for the electrodes of a diode?",
      "answer": "Anode and cathode"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following can provide power gain?",
      "answer": "Transistor"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the term that describes a device's ability to amplify a signal?",
      "answer": "Gain"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the names of the electrodes of a bipolar junction transistor?",
      "answer": "Emitter, base, collector"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of an electrical wiring diagram that uses standard component symbols?",
      "answer": "Schematic"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is component 1 in figure T1?",
      "answer": "Resistor"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is component 2 in figure T1?",
      "answer": "Transistor"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is component 3 in figure T1?",
      "answer": "Lamp"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is component 4 in figure T1?",
      "answer": "Battery"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is component 6 in figure T2?",
      "answer": "Capacitor"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is component 8 in figure T2?",
      "answer": "Light emitting diode"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is component 9 in figure T2?",
      "answer": "Variable resistor"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is component 4 in figure T2?",
      "answer": "Transformer"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is component 3 in figure T3?",
      "answer": "Variable inductor"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is component 4 in figure T3?",
      "answer": "Antenna"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is accurately represented in electrical schematics?",
      "answer": "Component connections"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following devices or circuits changes an alternating current into a varying direct current signal?",
      "answer": "Rectifier"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a relay?",
      "answer": "An electrically-controlled switch"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a reason to use shielded wire?",
      "answer": "To prevent coupling of unwanted signals to or from the wire"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following displays an electrical quantity as a numeric value?",
      "answer": "Meter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of circuit controls the amount of voltage from a power supply?",
      "answer": "Regulator"
    },
    {
      "question": "What component changes 120 V AC power to a lower AC voltage for other uses?",
      "answer": "Transformer"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is commonly used as a visual indicator?",
      "answer": "LED"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is combined with an inductor to make a resonant circuit?",
      "answer": "Capacitor"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of a device that combines several semiconductors and other components into one package?",
      "answer": "Integrated circuit"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the function of component 2 in figure T-1?",
      "answer": "Control the flow of current"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a resonant or tuned circuit?",
      "answer": "An inductor and a capacitor in series or parallel"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which term describes the ability of a receiver to detect the presence of a signal?",
      "answer": "Sensitivity"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a transceiver?",
      "answer": "A device that combines a receiver and transmitter"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is used to convert a signal from one frequency to another?",
      "answer": "Mixer"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which term describes the ability of a receiver to discriminate between multiple signals?",
      "answer": "Selectivity"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of a circuit that generates a signal at a specific frequency?",
      "answer": "Oscillator"
    },
    {
      "question": "What device converts the RF input and output of a transceiver to another band?",
      "answer": "Transverter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the function of a transceiver's PTT input?",
      "answer": "Switches transceiver from receive to transmit when grounded"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following describes combining speech with an RF carrier signal?",
      "answer": "Modulation"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the function of the SSB/CW-FM switch on a VHF power amplifier?",
      "answer": "Set the amplifier for proper operation in the selected mode"
    },
    {
      "question": "What device increases the transmitted output power from a transceiver?",
      "answer": "An RF power amplifier"
    },
    {
      "question": "Where is an RF preamplifier installed?",
      "answer": "Between the antenna and receiver"
    },
    {
      "question": "What can you do if you are told your FM handheld or mobile transceiver is over-deviating?",
      "answer": "Talk farther away from the microphone"
    },
    {
      "question": "What would cause a broadcast AM or FM radio to receive an amateur radio transmission unintentionally?",
      "answer": "The receiver is unable to reject strong signals outside the AM or FM band"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following can cause radio frequency interference?",
      "answer": "All these choices are correct"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following could you use to cure distorted audio caused by RF current on the shield of a microphone cable?",
      "answer": "Ferrite choke"
    },
    {
      "question": "How can fundamental overload of a non-amateur radio or TV receiver by an amateur signal be reduced or eliminated?",
      "answer": "Block the amateur signal with a filter at the antenna input of the affected receiver"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following actions should you take if a neighbor tells you that your station’s transmissions are interfering with their radio or TV reception?",
      "answer": "Make sure that your station is functioning properly and that it does not cause interference to your own radio or television when it is tuned to the same channel"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following can reduce overload of a VHF transceiver by a nearby commercial FM station?",
      "answer": "Installing a band-reject filter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What should you do if something in a neighbor’s home is causing harmful interference to your amateur station?",
      "answer": "All these choices are correct"
    },
    {
      "question": "What should be the first step to resolve non-fiber optic cable TV interference caused by your amateur radio transmission?",
      "answer": "Be sure all TV feed line coaxial connectors are installed properly"
    },
    {
      "question": "What might be a problem if you receive a report that your audio signal through an FM repeater is distorted or unintelligible?",
      "answer": "All these choices are correct"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a symptom of RF feedback in a transmitter or transceiver?",
      "answer": "Reports of garbled, distorted, or unintelligible voice transmissions"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the primary purpose of a dummy load?",
      "answer": "To prevent transmitting signals over the air when making tests"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is used to determine if an antenna is resonant at the desired operating frequency?",
      "answer": "An antenna analyzer"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does a dummy load consist of?",
      "answer": "A non-inductive resistor mounted on a heat sink"
    },
    {
      "question": "What reading on an SWR meter indicates a perfect impedance match between the antenna and the feed line?",
      "answer": "1:1"
    },
    {
      "question": "Why do most solid-state transmitters reduce output power as SWR increases beyond a certain level?",
      "answer": "To protect the output amplifier transistors"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does an SWR reading of 4:1 indicate?",
      "answer": "Impedance mismatch"
    },
    {
      "question": "What happens to power lost in a feed line?",
      "answer": "It is converted into heat"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which instrument can be used to determine SWR?",
      "answer": "Directional wattmeter"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following causes failure of coaxial cables?",
      "answer": "Moisture contamination"
    },
    {
      "question": "Why should the outer jacket of coaxial cable be resistant to ultraviolet light?",
      "answer": "Ultraviolet light can damage the jacket and allow water to enter the cable"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a disadvantage of air core coaxial cable when compared to foam or solid dielectric types?",
      "answer": "It requires special techniques to prevent moisture in the cable"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which instrument would you use to measure electric potential?",
      "answer": "A voltmeter"
    },
    {
      "question": "How is a voltmeter connected to a component to measure applied voltage?",
      "answer": "In parallel"
    },
    {
      "question": "When configured to measure current, how is a multimeter connected to a component?",
      "answer": "In series"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which instrument is used to measure electric current?",
      "answer": "An ammeter"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following can damage a multimeter?",
      "answer": "Attempting to measure voltage when using the resistance setting"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following measurements are made using a multimeter?",
      "answer": "Voltage and resistance"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following types of solder should not be used for radio and electronic applications?",
      "answer": "Acid-core solder"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the characteristic appearance of a cold tin-lead solder joint?",
      "answer": "A rough or lumpy surface"
    },
    {
      "question": "What reading indicates that an ohmmeter is connected across a large, discharged capacitor?",
      "answer": "Increasing resistance with time"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following precautions should be taken when measuring in-circuit resistance with an ohmmeter?",
      "answer": "Ensure that the circuit is not powered"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a form of amplitude modulation?",
      "answer": "Single sideband"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of modulation is commonly used for VHF packet radio transmissions?",
      "answer": "FM or PM"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which type of voice mode is often used for long-distance (weak signal) contacts on the VHF and UHF bands?",
      "answer": "SSB"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which type of modulation is commonly used for VHF and UHF voice repeaters?",
      "answer": "FM or PM"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following types of signal has the narrowest bandwidth?",
      "answer": "CW"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which sideband is normally used for 10 meter HF, VHF, and UHF single-sideband communications?",
      "answer": "Upper sideband"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a characteristic of single sideband (SSB) compared to FM?",
      "answer": "SSB signals have narrower bandwidth"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the approximate bandwidth of a typical single sideband (SSB) voice signal?",
      "answer": "3 kHz"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the approximate bandwidth of a VHF repeater FM voice signal?",
      "answer": "Between 10 and 15 kHz"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the approximate bandwidth of AM fast-scan TV transmissions?",
      "answer": "About 6 MHz"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the approximate bandwidth required to transmit a CW signal?",
      "answer": "150 Hz"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a disadvantage of FM compared with single sideband?",
      "answer": "Only one signal can be received at a time"
    },
    {
      "question": "What telemetry information is typically transmitted by satellite beacons?",
      "answer": "Health and status of the satellite"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the impact of using excessive effective radiated power on a satellite uplink?",
      "answer": "Blocking access by other users"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following are provided by satellite tracking programs?",
      "answer": "All these choices are correct"
    },
    {
      "question": "What mode of transmission is commonly used by amateur radio satellites?",
      "answer": "All these choices are correct"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a satellite beacon?",
      "answer": "A transmission from a satellite that contains status information"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following are inputs to a satellite tracking program?",
      "answer": "The Keplerian elements"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is Doppler shift in reference to satellite communications?",
      "answer": "An observed change in signal frequency caused by relative motion between the satellite and Earth station"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is meant by the statement that a satellite is operating in U/V mode?",
      "answer": "The satellite uplink is in the 70 centimeter band and the downlink is in the 2 meter band"
    },
    {
      "question": "What causes spin fading of satellite signals?",
      "answer": "Rotation of the satellite and its antennas"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a LEO satellite?",
      "answer": "A satellite in low earth orbit"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who may receive telemetry from a space station?",
      "answer": "Anyone"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a way to determine whether your satellite uplink power is neither too low nor too high?",
      "answer": "Your signal strength on the downlink should be about the same as the beacon"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following methods is used to locate sources of noise interference or jamming?",
      "answer": "Radio direction finding"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these items would be useful for a hidden transmitter hunt?",
      "answer": "A directional antenna"
    },
    {
      "question": "What operating activity involves contacting as many stations as possible during a specified period?",
      "answer": "Contesting"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is good procedure when contacting another station in a contest?",
      "answer": "Send only the minimum information needed for proper identification and the contest exchange"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a grid locator?",
      "answer": "A letter-number designator assigned to a geographic location"
    },
    {
      "question": "How is over the air access to IRLP nodes accomplished?",
      "answer": "By using DTMF signals"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is Voice Over Internet Protocol (VoIP)?",
      "answer": "A method of delivering voice communications over the internet using digital techniques"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the Internet Radio Linking Project (IRLP)?",
      "answer": "A technique to connect amateur radio systems, such as repeaters, via the internet using Voice Over Internet Protocol (VoIP)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following protocols enables an amateur station to transmit through a repeater without using a radio to initiate the transmission?",
      "answer": "EchoLink"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is required before using the EchoLink system?",
      "answer": "Register your call sign and provide proof of license"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is an amateur radio station that connects other amateur stations to the internet?",
      "answer": "A gateway"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a digital communications mode?",
      "answer": "All these choices are correct"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a “talkgroup” on a DMR repeater?",
      "answer": "A way for groups of users to share a channel at different times without hearing other users on the channel"
    },
    {
      "question": "What kind of data can be transmitted by APRS?",
      "answer": "All these choices are correct"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of transmission is indicated by the term \"NTSC?\"",
      "answer": "An analog fast-scan color TV signal"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is an application of APRS?",
      "answer": "Providing real-time tactical digital communications in conjunction with a map showing the locations of stations"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the abbreviation \"PSK\" mean?",
      "answer": "Phase Shift Keying"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following describes DMR?",
      "answer": "A technique for time-multiplexing two digital voice signals on a single 12.5 kHz repeater channel"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is included in packet radio transmissions?",
      "answer": "All these choices are correct"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is CW?",
      "answer": "Another name for a Morse code transmission"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following operating activities is supported by digital mode software in the WSJT-X software suite?",
      "answer": "All these choices are correct"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is an ARQ transmission system?",
      "answer": "An error correction method in which the receiving station detects errors and sends a request for retransmission"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following best describes an amateur radio mesh network?",
      "answer": "An amateur-radio based data network using commercial Wi-Fi equipment with modified firmware"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is FT8?",
      "answer": "A digital mode capable of low signal-to-noise operation"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a beam antenna?",
      "answer": "An antenna that concentrates signals in one direction"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following describes a type of antenna loading?",
      "answer": "Electrically lengthening by inserting inductors in radiating elements"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following describes a simple dipole oriented parallel to Earth's surface?",
      "answer": "A horizontally polarized antenna"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a disadvantage of the short, flexible antenna supplied with most handheld radio transceivers, compared to a full-sized quarter-wave antenna?",
      "answer": "It has low efficiency"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following increases the resonant frequency of a dipole antenna?",
      "answer": "Shortening it"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following types of antenna offers the greatest gain?",
      "answer": "Yagi"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a disadvantage of using a handheld VHF transceiver with a flexible antenna inside a vehicle?",
      "answer": "Signal strength is reduced due to the shielding effect of the vehicle"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the approximate length, in inches, of a quarter-wavelength vertical antenna for 146 MHz?",
      "answer": "19"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the approximate length, in inches, of a half-wavelength 6 meter dipole antenna?",
      "answer": "112"
    },
    {
      "question": "In which direction does a half-wave dipole antenna radiate the strongest signal?",
      "answer": "Broadside to the antenna"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is antenna gain?",
      "answer": "The increase in signal strength in a specified direction compared to a reference antenna"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is an advantage of a 5/8 wavelength whip antenna for VHF or UHF mobile service?",
      "answer": "It has more gain than a 1/4-wavelength antenna"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a benefit of low SWR?",
      "answer": "Reduced signal loss"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the most common impedance of coaxial cables used in amateur radio?",
      "answer": "50 ohms"
    },
    {
      "question": "Why is coaxial cable the most common feed line for amateur radio antenna systems?",
      "answer": "It is easy to use and requires few special installation considerations"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the major function of an antenna tuner (antenna coupler)?",
      "answer": "It matches the antenna system impedance to the transceiver's output impedance"
    },
    {
      "question": "What happens as the frequency of a signal in coaxial cable is increased?",
      "answer": "The loss increases"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following RF connector types is most suitable for frequencies above 400 MHz?",
      "answer": "Type N"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is true of PL-259 type coax connectors?",
      "answer": "They are commonly used at HF and VHF frequencies"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a source of loss in coaxial feed line?",
      "answer": "All these choices are correct"
    },
    {
      "question": "What can cause erratic changes in SWR?",
      "answer": "Loose connection in the antenna or feed line"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the electrical difference between RG-58 and RG-213 coaxial cable?",
      "answer": "RG-213 cable has less loss at a given frequency"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following types of feed line has the lowest loss at VHF and UHF?",
      "answer": "Air-insulated hardline"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is standing wave ratio (SWR)?",
      "answer": "A measure of how well a load is matched to a transmission line"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a safety hazard of a 12-volt storage battery?",
      "answer": "Shorting the terminals can cause burns, fire, or an explosion"
    },
    {
      "question": "What health hazard is presented by electrical current flowing through the body?",
      "answer": "All these choices are correct"
    },
    {
      "question": "In the United States, what circuit does black wire insulation indicate in a three-wire 120 V cable?",
      "answer": "Hot"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of a fuse in an electrical circuit?",
      "answer": "To remove power in case of overload"
    },
    {
      "question": "Why should a 5-ampere fuse never be replaced with a 20-ampere fuse?",
      "answer": "Excessive current could cause a fire"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a good way to guard against electrical shock at your station?",
      "answer": "All these choices are correct"
    },
    {
      "question": "Where should a lightning arrester be installed in a coaxial feed line?",
      "answer": "On a grounded panel near where feed lines enter the building"
    },
    {
      "question": "Where should a fuse or circuit breaker be installed in a 120V AC power circuit?",
      "answer": "In series with the hot conductor only"
    },
    {
      "question": "What should be done to all external ground rods or earth connections?",
      "answer": "Bond them together with heavy wire or conductive strap"
    },
    {
      "question": "What hazard is caused by charging or discharging a battery too quickly?",
      "answer": "Overheating or out-gassing"
    },
    {
      "question": "What hazard exists in a power supply immediately after turning it off?",
      "answer": "Charge stored in filter capacitors"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following precautions should be taken when measuring high voltages with a voltmeter?",
      "answer": "Ensure that the voltmeter and leads are rated for use at the voltages to be measured"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is good practice when installing ground wires on a tower for lightning protection?",
      "answer": "Ensure that connections are short and direct"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is required when climbing an antenna tower?",
      "answer": "All these choices are correct"
    },
    {
      "question": "Under what circumstances is it safe to climb a tower without a helper or observer?",
      "answer": "Never"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is an important safety precaution to observe when putting up an antenna tower?",
      "answer": "Look for and stay clear of any overhead electrical wires"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of a safety wire through a turnbuckle used to tension guy lines?",
      "answer": "Prevent loosening of the turnbuckle from vibration"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the minimum safe distance from a power line to allow when installing an antenna?",
      "answer": "Enough so that if the antenna falls, no part of it can come closer than 10 feet to the power wires"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is an important safety rule to remember when using a crank-up tower?",
      "answer": "This type of tower must not be climbed unless it is retracted, or mechanical safety locking devices have been installed"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is a proper grounding method for a tower?",
      "answer": "Separate eight-foot ground rods for each tower leg, bonded to the tower and each other"
    },
    {
      "question": "Why should you avoid attaching an antenna to a utility pole?",
      "answer": "The antenna could contact high-voltage power lines"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is true when installing grounding conductors used for lightning protection?",
      "answer": "Sharp bends must be avoided"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following establishes grounding requirements for an amateur radio tower or antenna?",
      "answer": "Local electrical codes"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of radiation are radio signals?",
      "answer": "Non-ionizing radiation"
    },
    {
      "question": "At which of the following frequencies does maximum permissible exposure have the lowest value?",
      "answer": "50 MHz"
    },
    {
      "question": "How does the allowable power density for RF safety change if duty cycle changes from 100 percent to 50 percent?",
      "answer": "It increases by a factor of 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "What factors affect the RF exposure of people near an amateur station antenna?",
      "answer": "All these choices are correct"
    },
    {
      "question": "Why do exposure limits vary with frequency?",
      "answer": "The human body absorbs more RF energy at some frequencies than at others"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is an acceptable method to determine whether your station complies with FCC RF exposure regulations?",
      "answer": "All these choices are correct"
    },
    {
      "question": "What hazard is created by touching an antenna during a transmission?",
      "answer": "RF burn to skin"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following actions can reduce exposure to RF radiation?",
      "answer": "Relocate antennas"
    },
    {
      "question": "How can you make sure your station stays in compliance with RF safety regulations?",
      "answer": "By re-evaluating the station whenever an item in the transmitter or antenna system is changed"
    },
    {
      "question": "Why is duty cycle one of the factors used to determine safe RF radiation exposure levels?",
      "answer": "It affects the average exposure to radiation"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the definition of duty cycle during the averaging time for RF exposure?",
      "answer": "The percentage of time that a transmitter is transmitting"
    },
    {
      "question": "How does RF radiation differ from ionizing radiation (radioactivity)?",
      "answer": "RF radiation does not have sufficient energy to cause chemical changes in cells and damage DNA"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is responsible for ensuring that no person is exposed to RF energy above the FCC exposure limits?",
      "answer": "The station licensee"
    }
  ],
  "General": [
    {
      "question": "On which HF and/or MF amateur bands are there portions where General class licensees cannot transmit?",
      "answer": "80 meters, 40 meters, 20 meters, and 15 meters"
    },
    {
      "question": "On which of the following bands is phone operation prohibited?",
      "answer": "30 Meters"
    },
    {
      "question": "On which of the following bands is image transmission prohibited?",
      "answer": "30 Meters"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following amateur bands is restricted to communication only on specific channels, rather than frequency ranges?",
      "answer": "60 Meters"
    },
    {
      "question": "On which of the following frequencies are General class licensees prohibited from operating as control operator?",
      "answer": "7.125 MHz to 7.175 MHz"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following applies when the FCC rules designate the amateur service as a secondary user on a band?",
      "answer": "Amateur stations must not cause harmful interference to primary users and must accept interference from primary users"
    },
    {
      "question": "On which amateur frequencies in the 10-meter band may stations with a General class control operator transmit CW emissions?",
      "answer": "The entire band"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which HF bands have segments exclusively allocated to Amateur Extra licensees?",
      "answer": "80 meters, 40 meters, 20 meters, and 15 meters"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following frequencies is within the General class portion of the 15-meter band?",
      "answer": "21300 kHz"
    },
    {
      "question": "What portion of the 10-meter band is available for repeater use?",
      "answer": "The portion above 29.5 MHz"
    },
    {
      "question": "When General class licensees are not permitted to use the entire voice portion of a band, which portion of the voice segment is available to them?",
      "answer": "The upper frequency portion"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the maximum height above ground for an antenna structure not near a public use airport without requiring notification to the FAA and registration with the FCC?",
      "answer": "200 Feet"
    },
    {
      "question": "With which of the following conditions must beacon stations comply?",
      "answer": "No more than one beacon station may transmit in the same band from the same station location"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a purpose of a beacon station as identified in the FCC rules?",
      "answer": "Observation of propagation and reception"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following transmissions is permitted for all amateur stations?",
      "answer": "Occasional retransmission of weather and propagation forecast information from US government stations"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following one-way transmissions are permitted?",
      "answer": "Transmissions to assist with learning the International Morse code"
    },
    {
      "question": "Under what conditions are state and local governments permitted to regulate amateur radio antenna structures?",
      "answer": "Amateur Service communications must be reasonably accommodated, and regulations must constitute the minimum practical to accommodate a legitimate purpose of the state or local entity"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the restrictions on the use of abbreviations or procedural signals in the amateur service?",
      "answer": "They may be used if they do not obscure the meaning of a message"
    },
    {
      "question": "When is it permissible to communicate with amateur stations in countries outside the areas administered by the Federal Communications Commission?",
      "answer": "When the contact is with amateurs in any country except those whose administrations have notified the ITU that they object to such communications"
    },
    {
      "question": "On what HF frequencies are automatically controlled beacons permitted?",
      "answer": "28.20 MHz to 28.30 MHz"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the power limit for beacon stations?",
      "answer": "100 watts PEP output"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who or what determines “good engineering and good amateur practice,” as applied to the operation of an amateur station in all respects not covered by the Part 97 rules?",
      "answer": "The FCC"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the maximum transmitter power an amateur station may use on 10.140 MHz?",
      "answer": "200 watts PEP output"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the maximum transmitter power an amateur station may use on the 12-meter band?",
      "answer": "1500 Watts PEP output"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the maximum bandwidth permitted by FCC rules for amateur radio stations transmitting on USB frequencies in the 60-meter band?",
      "answer": "2.8kHz"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is required by the FCC rules when operating in the 60-meter band?",
      "answer": "If you are using an antenna other than a dipole, you must keep a record of the gain of your antenna"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the limit for transmitter power on the 28 MHz band for a General Class control operator?",
      "answer": "1500 watts PEP output"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the limit for transmitter power on the 1.8 MHz band?",
      "answer": "1500 watts PEP output"
    },
    {
      "question": "What must be done before using a new digital protocol on the air?",
      "answer": "Publicly document the technical characteristics of the protocol"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the maximum power limit on the 60-meter band?",
      "answer": "ERP of 100 watts PEP with respect to a dipole"
    },
    {
      "question": "What measurement is specified by FCC rules that regulate maximum power?",
      "answer": "PEP output from the transmitter"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who may receive partial credit for the elements represented by an expired amateur radio license?",
      "answer": "Any person who can demonstrate that they once held an FCC-issued General, Advanced, or Amateur Extra class license that was not revoked by the FCC"
    },
    {
      "question": "What license examinations may you administer as an accredited Volunteer Examiner holding a General class operator license?",
      "answer": "Technician only"
    },
    {
      "question": "On which of the following band segments may you operate if you are a Technician class operator and have an unexpired Certificate of Successful Completion of Examination (CSCE) for General class privileges?",
      "answer": "On any General or Technician class band segment"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who must observe the administration of a Technician class license examination?",
      "answer": "At least three Volunteer Examiners of General class or higher"
    },
    {
      "question": "When operating a US station by remote control from outside the country, what license is required of the control operator?",
      "answer": "A US operator/primary station license"
    },
    {
      "question": "Until an upgrade to General class is shown in the FCC database, when must a Technician licensee identify with “AG” after their call sign?",
      "answer": "Whenever they operate using General class frequency privileges"
    },
    {
      "question": "Volunteer Examiners are accredited by what organization?",
      "answer": "A Volunteer Examiner Coordinator"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following criteria must be met for a non-US citizen to be an accredited Volunteer Examiner?",
      "answer": "The person must hold an FCC granted amateur radio license of General class or above"
    },
    {
      "question": "How long is a Certificate of Successful Completion of Examination (CSCE) valid for exam element credit?",
      "answer": "365 Days"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the minimum age that one must be to qualify as an accredited Volunteer Examiner?",
      "answer": "18 years"
    },
    {
      "question": "What action is required to obtain a new General class license after a previously held license has expired and the two-year grace period has passed?",
      "answer": "The applicant must show proof of the appropriate expired license grant and pass the current Element 2 exam"
    },
    {
      "question": "When operating a station in South America by remote control over the internet from the US, what regulations apply?",
      "answer": "Only those of the remote station's country"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following would disqualify a third party from participating in sending a message via an amateur station?",
      "answer": "The third party's amateur license has been revoked and not reinstated"
    },
    {
      "question": "When may a 10-meter repeater retransmit the 2-meter signal from a station that has a Technician class control operator?",
      "answer": "Only if the 10-meter repeater control operator holds at least a General class license"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is required to conduct communications with a digital station operating under automatic control outside the automatic control band segments?",
      "answer": "The station initiating the contact must be under local or remote control"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following conditions require a licensed amateur radio operator to take specific steps to avoid harmful interference to other users or facilities?",
      "answer": "All these choices are correct"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the restrictions on messages sent to a third party in a country with which there is a Third-Party Agreement?",
      "answer": "They must relate to amateur radio, or remarks of a personal character, or messages relating to emergencies or disaster relief"
    },
    {
      "question": "The frequency allocations of which ITU region apply to radio amateurs operating in North and South America?",
      "answer": "Region 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "In what part of the 2.4 GHz band may an amateur station communicate with non-licensed Wi-Fi stations?",
      "answer": "No Part"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the maximum PEP output allowed for spread spectrum transmissions?",
      "answer": "10 Watts"
    },
    {
      "question": "Under what circumstances are messages that are sent via digital modes exempt from Part 97 third-party rules that apply to other modes of communication?",
      "answer": "Under No Circumstances"
    },
    {
      "question": "Why should an amateur operator normally avoid transmitting on 14.100, 18.110, 21.150, 24.930 and 28.200 MHz?",
      "answer": "A system of propagation beacon stations operates on those frequencies"
    },
    {
      "question": "On what bands may automatically controlled stations transmitting RTTY or data emissions communicate with other automatically controlled digital stations?",
      "answer": "Anywhere in the 6-meter or shorter wavelength bands, and in limited segments of some of the HF bands"
    },
    {
      "question": "When may third-party messages be transmitted via remote control?",
      "answer": "Under any circumstances in which third party messages are permitted by FCC rules"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which mode is most commonly used for voice communications on frequencies of 14 MHz or higher?",
      "answer": "Upper sideband"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which mode is most commonly used for voice communications on the 160-, 75-, and 40-meter bands?",
      "answer": "Lower sideband"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which mode is most commonly used for SSB voice communications in the VHF and UHF bands?",
      "answer": "Upper sideband"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which mode is most commonly used for voice communications on the 17- and 12-meter bands?",
      "answer": "Upper sideband"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which mode of voice communication is most commonly used on the HF amateur bands?",
      "answer": "Single sideband"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is an advantage of using single sideband, as compared to other analog voice modes on the HF amateur bands?",
      "answer": "Less bandwidth used and greater power efficiency"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following statements is true of single sideband SSB?",
      "answer": "Only one sideband is transmitted; the other sideband and carrier are suppressed"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the recommended way to break into a phone contact?",
      "answer": "Say your call sign once"
    },
    {
      "question": "Why do most amateur stations use lower sideband on the 160-, 75-, and 40-meter bands?",
      "answer": "It is commonly accepted amateur practice"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following statements is true of VOX operation versus PTT operation?",
      "answer": "It allows “hands free” operation"
    },
    {
      "question": "Generally, who should respond to a station in the contiguous 48 states calling “CQ DX”?",
      "answer": "Any stations outside the lower 48 states"
    },
    {
      "question": "What control is typically adjusted for proper ALC setting on a single sideband transceiver?",
      "answer": "Transmit audio or microphone gain"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is true concerning access to frequencies?",
      "answer": "Except during emergencies, no amateur station has priority access to any frequency"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the first thing you should do if you are communicating with another amateur station and hear a station in distress break in?",
      "answer": "Acknowledge the station in distress and determine what assistance may be needed"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is good amateur practice if propagation changes during a contact creating interference from other stations using the frequency?",
      "answer": "Attempt to resolve the interference problem with the other stations in a mutually acceptable manner"
    },
    {
      "question": "When selecting a CW transmitting frequency, what minimum separation from other stations should be used to minimize interference to stations on adjacent frequencies?",
      "answer": "150 Hz to 500 Hz"
    },
    {
      "question": "When selecting an SSB transmitting frequency, what minimum separation should be used to minimize interference to stations on adjacent frequencies?",
      "answer": "2 kHz to 3 kHz"
    },
    {
      "question": "How can you avoid harmful interference on an apparently clear frequency before calling CQ on CW or phone?",
      "answer": "Send “QRL?” on CW, followed by your call sign; or, if using phone, ask if the frequency is in use, followed by your call sign"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following complies with commonly accepted amateur practice when choosing a frequency on which to initiate a call?",
      "answer": "Follow the voluntary band plan"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the voluntary band plan restriction for US stations transmitting within the 48 contiguous states in the 50.1 MHz to 50.125 MHz band segment?",
      "answer": "Only contacts with stations not within the 48 contiguous states"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who may be the control operator of an amateur station transmitting in RACES to assist relief operations during a disaster?",
      "answer": "Only a person holding an FCC-issued amateur operator license"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is good amateur practice for net management?",
      "answer": "Have a backup frequency in case of interference or poor conditions"
    },
    {
      "question": "How often may RACES training drills and tests be routinely conducted without special authorization?",
      "answer": "No more than 1 hour per week"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following describes full break in CW operation QSK ?",
      "answer": "Transmitting stations can receive between code characters and elements"
    },
    {
      "question": "What should you do if a CW station sends QRS ?",
      "answer": "Send slower"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does it mean when a CW operator sends KN at the end of a transmission?",
      "answer": "Listening only for a specific station or stations"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the Q signal QRL mean?",
      "answer": "Are you busy or Is this frequency in use"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the best speed to use when answering a CQ in Morse code?",
      "answer": "The fastest speed at which you are comfortable copying, but no faster than the CQ"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the term zero beat mean in CW operation?",
      "answer": "Matching the transmit frequency to the frequency of a received signal"
    },
    {
      "question": "When sending CW what does a C mean when added to the RST report?",
      "answer": "Chirpy or unstable signal"
    },
    {
      "question": "What prosign is sent to indicate the end of a formal message when using CW?",
      "answer": "AR"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the Q signal QSL mean?",
      "answer": "I have received and understood"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the Q signal QRN mean?",
      "answer": "I am troubled by static"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the Q signal QRV mean?",
      "answer": "I am ready to receive"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the Volunteer Monitor Program?",
      "answer": "Amateur volunteers who are formally enlisted to monitor the airwaves for rules violations"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following are objectives of the Volunteer Monitor Program?",
      "answer": "To encourage amateur radio operators to self-regulate and comply with the rules"
    },
    {
      "question": "What procedure may be used by Volunteer Monitors to localize a station whose continuous carrier is holding a repeater on in their area?",
      "answer": "Compare beam headings on the repeater input from their home locations with that of other Volunteer Monitors"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following describes an azimuthal projection map?",
      "answer": "A map that shows true bearings and distances from a specific location"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following indicates that you are looking for an HF contact with any station?",
      "answer": "Repeat “CQ” a few times, followed by “this is,” then your call sign a few times, then pause to listen, repeat as necessary"
    },
    {
      "question": "How is a directional antenna pointed when making a “long-path” contact with another station?",
      "answer": "180 degrees from the station's short-path heading"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following are examples of the NATO Phonetic Alphabet?",
      "answer": "Alpha, Bravo, Charlie, Delta"
    },
    {
      "question": "Why do many amateurs keep a station log?",
      "answer": "To help with a reply if the FCC requests information about your station"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is required when participating in a contest on HF frequencies?",
      "answer": "Identify your station according to normal FCC regulations"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is QRP operation?",
      "answer": "Low-power transmit operation"
    },
    {
      "question": "Why are signal reports typically exchanged at the beginning of an HF contact?",
      "answer": "To allow each station to operate according to conditions"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which mode is normally used when sending RTTY signals via AFSK with an SSB transmitter?",
      "answer": "LSB"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is VARA?",
      "answer": "A digital protocol used with Winlink"
    },
    {
      "question": "What symptoms may result from other signals interfering with a PACTOR or VARA transmission?",
      "answer": "All these choices are correct"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is good practice when choosing a transmitting frequency to answer a station calling CQ using FT8?",
      "answer": "Find a clear frequency during the alternate time slot to the calling station"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the standard sideband for JT65 JT9 FT4 or FT8 digital signal when using AFSK?",
      "answer": "USB"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the most common frequency shift for RTTY emissions in the amateur HF bands?",
      "answer": "170 Hz"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is required when using FT8?",
      "answer": "Computer time accurate to within approximately 1 second"
    },
    {
      "question": "In what segment of the 20-meter band are most digital mode operations commonly found?",
      "answer": "Between 14.070 MHz and 14.100 MHz"
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you join a contact between two stations using the PACTOR protocol?",
      "answer": "Joining an existing contact is not possible, PACTOR connections are limited to two stations"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a way to establish contact with a digital messaging system gateway station?",
      "answer": "Transmit a connect message on the station’s published frequency"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the primary purpose of an Amateur Radio Emergency Data Network (AREDN) mesh network?",
      "answer": "To provide high-speed data services during an emergency or community event"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following describes Winlink?",
      "answer": "All these choices are correct"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is another name for a Winlink Remote Message Server?",
      "answer": "Gateway"
    },
    {
      "question": "What could be wrong if you cannot decode an RTTY or other FSK signal even though it is apparently tuned in properly?",
      "answer": "All these choices are correct"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a common location for FT8?",
      "answer": "Approximately 14.074 MHz to 14.077 MHz"
    },
    {
      "question": "How does a higher sunspot number affect HF propagation?",
      "answer": "Higher sunspot numbers generally indicate a greater probability of good propagation at higher frequencies"
    },
    {
      "question": "What effect does a sudden ionospheric disturbance have on the daytime ionospheric propagation?",
      "answer": "It disrupts signals on lower frequencies more than those on higher frequencies"
    },
    {
      "question": "Approximately how long does it take the increased ultraviolet and X-ray radiation from a solar flare to affect radio propagation on Earth?",
      "answer": "8 Minutes"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following are the least reliable bands for long-distance communications during periods of low solar activity?",
      "answer": "15 meters, 12 meters, and 10 meters"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the solar flux index?",
      "answer": "A measure of solar radiation with a wavelength of 10.7 centimeters"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a geomagnetic storm?",
      "answer": "A temporary disturbance in Earth's geomagnetic field"
    },
    {
      "question": "At what point in the solar cycle does the 20-meter band usually support worldwide propagation during daylight hours?",
      "answer": "At any point"
    },
    {
      "question": "How can a geomagnetic storm affect HF propagation?",
      "answer": "Degrade high-latitude HF propagation"
    },
    {
      "question": "How can high geomagnetic activity benefit radio communications?",
      "answer": "Creates auroras that can reflect VHF signals"
    },
    {
      "question": "What causes HF propagation conditions to vary periodically in a 26- to 28-day cycle?",
      "answer": "Rotation of the Sun's surface layers around its axis"
    },
    {
      "question": "How long does it take a coronal mass ejection to affect radio propagation on Earth?",
      "answer": "15 Hours to several days"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the K-index measure?",
      "answer": "The short-term stability of Earth's geomagnetic field"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the A-index measure?",
      "answer": "The long-term stability of Earth's geomagnetic field"
    },
    {
      "question": "How is long distance radio communication usually affected by the charged particles that reach Earth from solar coronal holes?",
      "answer": "HF communication is disturbed"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a characteristic of skywave signals arriving at your location by both short-path and long-path propagation?",
      "answer": "A slightly delayed echo might be heard"
    },
    {
      "question": "What factors affect the MUF?",
      "answer": "All these choices are correct"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which frequency will have the least attenuation for long distance skip propagation?",
      "answer": "Just below the MUF"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a way to determine current propagation on a desired band from your station?",
      "answer": "Use a network of automated receiving stations on the internet to see where your transmissions are being received"
    },
    {
      "question": "How does the ionosphere affect radio waves with frequencies below the MUF and above the LUF?",
      "answer": "They are refracted back to Earth"
    },
    {
      "question": "What usually happens to radio waves with frequencies below the LUF?",
      "answer": "They are attenuated before reaching the destination"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does LUF stand for?",
      "answer": "The Lowest Usable Frequency for communications between two specific points"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does MUF stand for?",
      "answer": "The Maximum Usable Frequency for communications between two points"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the approximate maximum distance along the Earth's surface normally covered in one hop using the F2 region?",
      "answer": "2,500 Miles"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the approximate maximum distance along the Earth's surface normally covered in one hop using the E region?",
      "answer": "1,200 Miles"
    },
    {
      "question": "What happens to HF propagation when the LUF exceeds the MUF?",
      "answer": "Propagation via ordinary skywave communications is not possible over that path"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is typical of the lower HF frequencies during the summer?",
      "answer": "High levels of atmospheric noise or static"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which ionospheric region is closest to the surface of Earth?",
      "answer": "The D region"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is meant by the term critical frequency at a given incidence angle?",
      "answer": "The highest frequency which is refracted back to Earth"
    },
    {
      "question": "Why is skip propagation via the F2 region longer than that via the other ionospheric regions?",
      "answer": "Because it is the highest"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the term critical angle mean, as applied to radio wave propagation?",
      "answer": "The highest takeoff angle that will return a radio wave to Earth under specific ionospheric conditions"
    },
    {
      "question": "Why is long distance communication on the 40- 60- 80- and 160 meter bands more difficult during the day?",
      "answer": "The D region absorbs signals at these frequencies during daylight hours"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a characteristic of HF scatter?",
      "answer": "Signals have a fluttering sound"
    },
    {
      "question": "What makes HF scatter signals often sound distorted?",
      "answer": "Energy is scattered into the skip zone through several different paths"
    },
    {
      "question": "Why are HF scatter signals in the skip zone usually weak?",
      "answer": "Only a small part of the signal energy is scattered into the skip zone"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of propagation allows signals to be heard in the transmitting station's skip zone?",
      "answer": "Scatter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is near vertical incidence skywave NVIS propagation?",
      "answer": "Short distance MF or HF propagation at high elevation angles"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which ionospheric region is the most absorbent of signals below 10 MHz during daylight hours?",
      "answer": "The D region"
    },
    {
      "question": "G4A",
      "answer": "next section"
    }
  ],
  "Amature_Extra": [{}]
}
